<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sciathlon</title>
    <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sciathlon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright> Copyright © Sciathlon 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:18:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://Sciathlon.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:18:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 18:56:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>The Sciathlon blog Sciathlon is a blog about the science of sports, athletes and sports technology written by a scientist and athlete for other athletes that are interested in knowing more about it. The purpose of it is to get together a community of people who are curious about the science that goes into their sport and want to learn and share information and stories. The content you will find here will be around scientific publications about sports science, technologies developed for athletes, but it is also about sharing life experiences to help others in their journey to be the best athlete they can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal best of figure skaters in men&#39;s and ladie&#39;s events</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/personal_best_figure_skating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 13:28:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/personal_best_figure_skating/</guid>
      <description>code{white-space: pre;} pre:not([class]) { background-color: white; }  if (window.hljs) { hljs.configure({languages: []}); hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad(); if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) { window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0); } }  h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R_figure_skating_analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/r_figure_skating_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 12:55:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/r_figure_skating_analysis/</guid>
      <description>code{white-space: pre;} pre:not([class]) { background-color: white; }  if (window.hljs) { hljs.configure({languages: []}); hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad(); if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) { window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0); } }  h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to Expect at Winter Olympics 2018 for figure skating</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/what-to-expect-at-winter-olympics-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 18:57:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/what-to-expect-at-winter-olympics-2018/</guid>
      <description>The winter olympics are coming! It is an exciting time to celebrate our favorite sports and feel inspired to do better ourselves. It is going to be interesting this year with the doping ban for Russia as well as many unfortunate injuries and retirements. Figure skating is my favorite event because it is an incredibly beautiful and hard sport that I practised for a few years when I was young. It has been a sport in the Olympics since the first one in 1924 in Chamonix, France, and is often complained about because they are not measuring a time but are looking at technical and artistic components of the sport which can be very unfair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A History of Skiing</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/the-history-of-skiing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 13:38:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/the-history-of-skiing/</guid>
      <description>I started skiing at the age of 3 at the station in the Alps called the &amp;ldquo;Sept Laux&amp;rdquo; next to Grenoble, France. It was natural to me, but until now I never wondered for how long people have done it. Here is a brief history of how it all began.
The word ski comes from old Norse, a germanic language that was spoken in Scandinavia from the 8th to the late 14th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are Skis Made Of</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/what-are-skis-made-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 13:25:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/what-are-skis-made-of/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s skiing season and I&amp;rsquo;m very excited about it except&amp;hellip; I can&amp;rsquo;t ski because I busted my knees. However I am still very curious to know what makes what skis are made of, and what is the difference between a beginner ski and a pro ski, like we can expect to see at the olympics in Febuary this year.
So, without getting in detail about the history of skis (which you can find in this blog post ), they used to be made entirely of wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Sports Channels</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/best-sports-channels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:53:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/best-sports-channels/</guid>
      <description>TheGingerRunner  If you are interested in running and want to learn more about trails, races, athletes, training, gear, nutrition, there are amazing ressources out there that will teach and inspire you. I have compiled a little list of my favorite youtube channels that I have been following for years. The first one is my absolute favorite, it inspires me so much. The channel is called TheGingerRunner and is owned by Ethan Newberry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:46:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello athletes, welcome on my new platform Sciathlon. The goal for this website is to share findings in sports science and technology. I am a biologist so I am interested in everything related with an athlete&amp;rsquo;s health such as nutrition, genetics, injuries and conditions related to the kind of activity we do. Some sports involve animals, so I will also be covering their health in this context. I am also interested in the technology involved in sports such as equipment but also training and performance analysis programmes and apps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>