<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sciathlon</title>
    <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sciathlon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright> Copyright © Sciathlon 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:18:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://Sciathlon.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:18:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 18:56:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>The Sciathlon blog Sciathlon is a blog about the science of sports, athletes and sports technology written by a scientist and athlete for other athletes that are interested in knowing more about it. The purpose of it is to get together a community of people who are curious about the science that goes into their sport and want to learn and share information and stories. The content you will find here will be around scientific publications about sports science, technologies developed for athletes, but it is also about sharing life experiences to help others in their journey to be the best athlete they can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite trail race: Tencin 15km analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/tencin_15k_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 18:17:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/tencin_15k_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I am continuing my journey to learn awk and I finally managed to process (almost) an entire file today so let&amp;rsquo;s analyse the 2018 Tencin trail race. It was my first trail race of the season, and it kicks off the &amp;ldquo;challenge intercommunal du grésivaudan&amp;rdquo;, which is a set of 11 races in this region called the Grésivaudan which is a valley in between the two mountains of Belledonne and Chartreuse in the Alps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first half marathon and its data analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/my_first_half_marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 16:42:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/my_first_half_marathon/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I ran my first half marathon this spring and wanted to talk about my experience. I also analyzed the results of the race which I found on the Grenoble-Vizille website, so scroll down if you want to only look at the data science part of this article. I&amp;rsquo;ve only been running regularly for a year, and I&amp;rsquo;d been dreaming about this day since I started. It was still kind of a dream for the longest time, something that I wanted but was still only a concept until the day arrived and I realized: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m running a half marathon today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biathlon data analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/biathlon_data_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 22:25:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/biathlon_data_analysis/</guid>
      <description>The 2018 Winter Olympics finally kicked off! In honor of this, I asked a friend of mine who loves sports what data he would be interested in seeing in the sports that are in the winter Olympics and he answered &amp;ldquo;biathlon.&amp;rdquo; I found a website that collects lots of data on the sport called biathlonresults.com. I was really looking forward to the olympics this year, and France has a very famous biathlete, Martin Fourcade, so that makes me keen to look more into this sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triathlon pubmed analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/triathlon_pubmed_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 20:32:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/triathlon_pubmed_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Today I am using the RISmed package for R to analyze publications about triathlon. It is an amazing package to look through the Pubmed database for what they have on a certain subject. Pubmed is a NIH (USA) funded database which hosts articles about medicine and biology. Today, I am looking at studies that have been done on injuries, disease and human physiology that have to do with triathlon. I am not a triathlete yet, I am just focusing on running this year but it is on my radar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figure skating athletes&#39; personal best</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/personal_best_figure_skating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 20:32:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/personal_best_figure_skating/</guid>
      <description>Today I am writing another piece about figure skating, also another piece about data analysis in this event. But I am not focusing solely on the Olympics this time but on the best scoring athletes and the best scoring event of each athlete. There is a lot of data to go through, so let&amp;rsquo;s get right into it! The data comes from the (International skating Union) website which I downloaded on the 20/01/2018 (if you try my code and the results are different it might be because the data on the website has changed).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R figure skating analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/analysis_medal_per_athlete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 12:55:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/analysis_medal_per_athlete/</guid>
      <description>Analysing medals won per athlete/per country with R Today I am introducing a sneaky little data analysis using R on figure skating in the olympics. I have already written a piece on Figure skating and what I think is going to happen in the upcoming olympics. But I also want to look back at athletes who have competed and won a medal in the past Olympics. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of data science, this is how you can make very easy analysis of your favorite things in the world!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to Expect at Winter Olympics 2018 for figure skating</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/what-to-expect-at-winter-olympics-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 18:57:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/what-to-expect-at-winter-olympics-2018/</guid>
      <description>The winter olympics are coming! It is an exciting time to celebrate our favorite sports and feel inspired to do better ourselves. It is going to be interesting this year with the doping ban for Russia as well as many unfortunate injuries and retirements. Figure skating is my favorite event because it is an incredibly beautiful and hard sport that I practised for a few years when I was young. It has been a sport in the Olympics since the first one in 1924 in Chamonix, France, and is often complained about because they are not measuring a time but are looking at technical and artistic components of the sport which can be very unfair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A History of Skiing</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/the-history-of-skiing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 13:38:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/the-history-of-skiing/</guid>
      <description>I started skiing at the age of 3 at the station in the Alps called the &amp;ldquo;Sept Laux&amp;rdquo; next to Grenoble, France. It was natural to me, but until now I never wondered for how long people have done it. Here is a brief history of how it all began.
The word ski comes from old Norse, a germanic language that was spoken in Scandinavia from the 8th to the late 14th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Sports Youtube Channels</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/best-sports-channels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:53:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/best-sports-channels/</guid>
      <description>TheGingerRunner  If you are interested in running and want to learn more about trails, races, athletes, training, gear, nutrition, there are amazing ressources out there that will teach and inspire you. I have compiled a little list of my favorite youtube channels that I have been following for years. The first one is my absolute favorite, it inspires me so much. The channel is called TheGingerRunner and is owned by Ethan Newberry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:46:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello athletes, welcome on my new platform Sciathlon. The goal for this website is to share findings in sports science and technology. I am a biologist so I am interested in everything related with an athlete&amp;rsquo;s health such as nutrition, genetics, injuries and conditions related to the kind of activity we do. Some sports involve animals, so I will also be covering their health in this context. I am also interested in the technology involved in sports such as equipment but also training and performance analysis programmes and apps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>