<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis on Sciathlon</title>
    <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/tags/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analysis on Sciathlon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright> Copyright © Sciathlon 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 16:57:38 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://Sciathlon.github.io/tags/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Strava time vs distance data analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/strava_time_distance_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 16:57:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/strava_time_distance_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody, I have a new run data analysis today: from my own strava data! I have been much slower recently on the posts, I will probably be until the end of july, because of work for my PhD, so I&amp;rsquo;m sorry about that. I am using the rStrava package and the tutorial in its readme file to get my strava data and see how much my running has changed since a year ago when I started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Sclerosis and exercise</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/ms_and_exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 18:41:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/ms_and_exercise/</guid>
      <description>Hi athletes. I recently went to a Multiple Sclerosis (MS) conference in Paris organized by the ARSEP foundation, mostly to see what people are doing on the immunology side of the disease, and I started looking into the foundation a bit more and that&amp;rsquo;s how I started doing this article. Multiple sclerosis is an inflammatory disease of the Central Nervous System (CNS). It is an auto-immune disease which means that our own immune system attacks us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Athlete&#39;s foot and its treatment</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/athletesfoot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 20:55:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/athletesfoot/</guid>
      <description>Hi athletes, today we will be looking at data about a health issue that affects many athletes: athlete&amp;rsquo;s foot. It&amp;rsquo;s not a very glamorous subject but it&amp;rsquo;s still interesting, and I find fungi really fascinating, they are warrior eukaryotes that survive everywhere! Most of you probably would rather never hear about it&amp;hellip; but you should. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, it is generally a fungal infection on the feet referred to as &amp;ldquo;tinea pedis&amp;rdquo; but can be something else that causes inflammation on the foot of an athlete, however the definitions vary according to who you talk to&amp;hellip; I am going to stick to the more accepted definition which is the fungal infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running races and waste</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/running_and_waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 13:37:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/running_and_waste/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I am tackling a new topic today, which is: waste generated during races. I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you why this is coming up now. I started the racing season with a road 10km called Asparun which was a relatively small race, 354 runners on the 10k plus probably as many on the 5k, which is more people than I usually see at my small local races, and I saw so many people just throwing their water goblets not IN the trash but sometimes 500 meters away, and it shocked me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite trail race: Tencin 15km analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/tencin_15k_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 18:17:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/tencin_15k_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I am continuing my journey to learn awk and I finally managed to process (almost) an entire file today so let&amp;rsquo;s analyse the 2018 Tencin trail race. It was my first trail race of the season, and it kicks off the &amp;ldquo;challenge intercommunal du grésivaudan&amp;rdquo;, which is a set of 11 races in this region called the Grésivaudan which is a valley in between the two mountains of Belledonne and Chartreuse in the Alps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first half marathon and its data analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/my_first_half_marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 16:42:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/my_first_half_marathon/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I ran my first half marathon this spring and wanted to talk about my experience. I also analyzed the results of the race which I found on the Grenoble-Vizille website, so scroll down if you want to only look at the data science part of this article. I&amp;rsquo;ve only been running regularly for a year, and I&amp;rsquo;d been dreaming about this day since I started. It was still kind of a dream for the longest time, something that I wanted but was still only a concept until the day arrived and I realized: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m running a half marathon today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biathlon data analysis</title>
      <link>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/biathlon_data_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 22:25:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Sciathlon.github.io/post/biathlon_data_analysis/</guid>
      <description>The 2018 Winter Olympics finally kicked off! In honor of this, I asked a friend of mine who loves sports what data he would be interested in seeing in the sports that are in the winter Olympics and he answered &amp;ldquo;biathlon.&amp;rdquo; I found a website that collects lots of data on the sport called biathlonresults.com. I was really looking forward to the olympics this year, and France has a very famous biathlete, Martin Fourcade, so that makes me keen to look more into this sport.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>